UNITE Research Department Historic Files 6000/003
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE Research Department Historic Files
1930-1999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
6000/003
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Compilation of ILGWU and ACTWU files from UNITE Research Department.
5748406
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 08, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 24, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6000/020: UNITE Research Department Files 6000/014: UNITE Research Department Chronological Correspondence Files 6000/020 P: UNITE Research Department Photographs 6000 AV: UNITE Audio-Visual Collection 6000 G: UNITE Posters 6000 MB: UNITE Memorabilia 6000 P: UNITE Photographs
Textile industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Textile workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing trade -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization)
5748406
- A210 TWUA Reports, 1938-1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  "Industrial Price Policies" - 1938; "A Trade-union Price Program" - April 14, 1947, "Industrial Price and Policies Need Revision" - March 19, 1947
- Committee On Ways and Means to Solomon Barkin On Closing Tax Loopholes, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A212 Statement of Solomon Barkin on behalf of Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  February 14, 1950
- B108 Stopping Sexual Harassment At Work (Box 1, Folder 4)
- B113 ACTWU Drug Testing, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- B115 Sweatshops, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- B115 Sweatshops, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- A705 Alaskan Oil Exports, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- A303 Labor and Economics Conversion, 1984-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- B116 ACWU, U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1939-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- B116 Regulations Applicable to Employment of Handicapped Persons, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- H 306 The Competitive Challenges to ACTW, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- B308 TWUA memo Re: Conference On An Agenda For Economic Research On Productivity, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  April 16, 1973
- B307 Discussions II - Unions, Machinery, & Allied Products Institute, IUPA, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- B505 CIO Proposals on Wage Data Collection, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- B307 Discussions II on Productivity, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- B307 Discussions On Productivity, 1960-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- B307 Discussions III on Productivity, 1952-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- B600 ILGWU SUBF, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- B603 Division of Work, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- B603 Division of Work II, 1975-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- B605 TWUA Severance Pay and Plant Closing, 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- B605 TWUA Severance Pay II, 1932-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- B605 Redundancy Act of 1965, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- B605 Separation Allowance, Dismissal Compensation, Severance Pay, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- B605 Severance Pay, Personnel Management, 1958-1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- B605 Dismissal Wages and Severance Pay, 1946-1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- B605 U.S. Legislation for Severance Pay, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- B606 Vacations, 1963-1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- B606 UNITE Research: Vacations, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  January 23, 1998
- B606 Vacations II, 1937-1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- B607 Productivity, Profit Sharing, 1947-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- B606 Vacations with pay, 1943-1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- B610 Solomon Barkin on Low-Income groups, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- I402 TWUA Clothing Stamps, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- I104 A Report On The Plight Of The Collective bargaining System, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  January 1984
- I403 Textiles buyouts and mergers, 1975-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- I403 TWUA Analyses, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- I403 TWUA Analyses, Mergers, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- I403 FTC to TWUA on mergers, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- I404 TWUA Statements, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- I404 Analyses of textile industry, 1952-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- I404 Wage data for textile workers, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- I404 Textile industry data, 1970-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- I404 Worker Data, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- I404 Southern workers, 1953-1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- I104 The Changing Situations Of Workers And Their Unions, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- I404 The Negro In The Textile Industry, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- I404 Industry, Sex, and Race data1, 1960-1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- I404 Air Conditioning, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- I405 Tech Changes in textile Industry, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- I406 Textile Productivity, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- I406 Textile Productivity, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- I406 Output Reports, 1958-1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- I406 Textile Productivity ACTWU Analysis, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- I503 A Trade Policy For Textiles, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- I505 Tariff Commission Wilton and Velvet, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- I508 Man-made Twine and H.R. 5629, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- I607 D.O.L. Reporting and Disclosure, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- I607 Union Pensions, 1980-1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- I610 Worker Compensation Data, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- I703 Footwear Production in Puerto Rico, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- I802 Italian Unionism in Chicago's Mens Garment Industry, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- I804 Men's and boys' suit and coat industry, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- B114 Illegal Aliens, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- B114 Illegal Aliens, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- B116 FLSA Handicapped Workers - Sheltered Workers Advisory Committee - Meetings, 1939-1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- B116 FLSA Handicapped Workers - Sheltered Workers Advisory Committee - Surveys, 1939-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- B201 TWUA Statement Before the Surplus Manpower Committee, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  March 24, 1952
- B201 Regarding the Apparel Industry, 1962-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- B201 Manpower, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- B201 Training, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- B203 Manpower, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- J105 Area Redevelopment Act, 1954-1965 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 337 A-O Wool Products Labeling Act Rule 36, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- B410 TWUA, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- B410 AFL-CIO, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- B411 TWUA, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- B109 Women Workers - Protective Labor Legislation and Women's Rights Legislation, 1955-1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- B109 Women Workers - General, 1940-1969 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- B110 Childcare - ACWA/ACTWU, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- I608 Social Security, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- I608 Social Security, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- I608 Social Security, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- I608 Social Security, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- I608 Social Security, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- I608 Social Security, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- I608 Social Security, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- I608 Social Security News Clippings, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- I608 Social Security, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- I608 Social Security, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- I608 Social Security, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- I608 Social Security, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- I608 Social Security, 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- I608 Social Security, 1930-1949 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- I608 Canada Pension System, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- I609 Unemployment Laws, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- I609 New York State Unemployment Insurance Historical, 1938-1949 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- I602 Public Interests, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- I601 Women's Health Care, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Single Payer Call-ins, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Elderly, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- African American, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- I601 Consumer Press, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- I601 ACTWU, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- I601 Latino, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- I601 Immigrants, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- I601 Healthcare for Youth, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- I601 Child Health, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- I601 Congressional Testimony, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- I601 ACTWU Cotton Dust, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- I601 Healthcare, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- I601 AFL-CIO, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- I601 Other Unions, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- I601 Bargaining, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- I601 Bargaining, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- I601 Organizing around, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- B101 Civil Rights, 1950-1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- B105 Homework, ACTWU and Other Materials, Lifting Ban in Women's Apparel, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- B107 Pay Equity, comparable worth, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- B103 Child Labor F.L.S.A. Requirements, 1959-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- B103 Child Labor, 1972-1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- B105 Tom Thumb Case: F.L.S.A., 1986 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- B105 F.L.S.A.: Homework, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- B105 F.L.S.A. Homework, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- B105 F.L.S.A. Homework (clips only), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- B105 Federal Register - Lifting Ban, Women's Apparel, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- B107 Women Workers, Equal Pay/Work for Retail salesmen/women, 1963-1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- B105 Homework Fed Regs + Government Documents, 1964-1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- B314 Plant Closing Legislation HR2847 Hearing Union Testimony, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  May 4, 1983
- B314 Plant Closing Nat'l Legislation Closing Notice, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- B314 Plant Closings, 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- B105 ILGWU Homework Hearings, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- B105 Industrial Homework, 1936-1941 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- B105 Industrial Homework, 1930-1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- B105 Industrial Homework Court Cases, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- B105 Homework Misc., 1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- B105 Homework Pro/con Articles, 1980-1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- B105 Homework Sheinkman Testimony, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Women's Economic Roundtable, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- The Joint Job Training And Research Corporation, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Industrial Cooperation Council, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- ICF, Incorporated, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- European Trade Union Institute, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Equality Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Emmanuel Weintraub Associates, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Council On Competitiveness, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- British - North American Committee, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- American Job training and Research Corp, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- American Labor Education Center, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- American Knit Glove Association, 1950-1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)